masterofmalt.com 2019-06-07

# Privacy Policy - Master of Malt

We are committed to protecting your privacy. Please take a minute to read this document which, together with our Cookie Policy (the **Privacy Policy** ) explains how we process your personal information and the choices you have.  By proceeding to use this site, you are accepting and consenting to the terms of this Privacy Policy and to the way we process your personal information.

**Important Note: We use MailChimp as our marketing automation platform. By proceeding to use this site, you acknowledge that the information you provide will be transferred to MailChimp for processing in accordance with their**[ **Privacy Policy**](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) **and their**[ **Terms**](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms) **.**

### SUMMARY

  * We take your privacy very seriously indeed. If you don’t want us to contact you for promotional purposes, we won’t (we will, of course, communicate with you in connection with any order you place, including order confirmation e-mails about that order). We will never sell your information.
  * We collect information to allow you to place orders with us and to improve your experience using our website. In particular, we diligently collect, track and interpret all data, including your personal information, which help to reveal what users generally, and you specifically, like and don’t like about our website, content and advertising.
  * We may share data with strategic, trusted partners (who may be located outside of the European Economic Area) so that we can better understand and improve the visitor experience, and cater to your preferences.
  * You can always find out what information we hold about you, and you can always opt-out, anytime, day or night (even on high holidays).  
  * If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, [please get in touch](mailto:gdpr@atomsupplies.com).

### WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

**Information you give us when you:**

  * register to use our website or create an account;
  * search for a product;
  * place an order;
  * subscribe to any update service;
  * participate in social media functions on the site;
  * enter information on certain pages on the site;
  * login using your social media profile;
  * contact us by phone or email; or
  * participate in a lottery, auction, competition or promotion.

This information may include your date of birth, name, email address, phone number and social media profile details); transaction details, purchase history and items saved on your basket; payment information and bank details such as your credit or debit card number and other card information, as well as billing and shipping details; and any other information we may ask in connection with promotional offers or other marketing activities. **Information we collect using cookies and other tracking technologies** relating to your use of our website and to your experience using our website (including the full URL clickstream to, through and from our site, download errors, methods used to browse away from each page, any phone number used to call our customer service number, device information, IP address, usage and location data). In basic terms, we will collect as much information about your use of our website as we possibly can. In our experience, this is the best way of improving the experience of visitors to the website. Oh, and just because other websites don’t tell you that they do this, doesn’t mean that they don’t! The tools which we use to monitor the functioning of our website collect certain data which users enter when interacting with that website, including personal data such as IP addresses, even if those users do not complete a purchase, post a comment, submit a review, enter a lottery or competition, bid in an auction or complete any other type of interaction with our website. We will never record passwords or credit card details in this way.  **Information we receive from other sources** , such as when somebody buys a gift for you on our site and from partners we jointly offer services with or from advertisers, about your interactions with them. This may comprise your name, geographic location, age, shopping habits, user-generated content (such as blogs and social media postings), social media username or other social media profile information (such as number of followers), in each case as permitted by law. We rely on the lawful basis for processing (which could be the consent you give to third parties) prior to us receiving that information for processing. Refer to the third party privacy statements of each of the websites you interact with for further details of that party’s processing.  

### HOW DO WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?

We use the **information you give to us** to:

  * process any order that you make and make sure you have a great experience using our services. The personal information you submit during your registration or while placing an order will only be used for the purpose of processing your orders unless you also opt in to receive a newsletter or marketing emails. We won’t use such data for marketing or other purposes unless you give us your permission to do so;
  * to provide customer service and support and to respond to your queries and requests;
  * notify you that you have been selected as a winner of a contest or sweepstake (or to confirm your entry to future competitions or events);
  * protect and prevent against fraud;
  * enable our experts to conduct data analysis to help us improve our services and advertising, including showing you our adverts as you browse the web. We also anonymise and aggregate personal information (so that it does not identify you) and use it for purposes including testing our IT systems, research, data analysis, improving our site and app, and developing new products and services; 
  * we may also send locally hashed data to trusted third parties (including but not limited to Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest, Snapchat, etc) to send you personalised advertising on those platforms  that you are already a member of and to help us create so-called “lookalike audiences” and/or “custom audiences” which will help us send relevant advertising to existing users of those platforms who may have similar taste in drinks and spirits; and
  * keep you updated on our latest announcements or send you marketing information about us and our products. If you would like to change your communication preferences or if you no longer want to be part of our mailing list, please either log into your account or [contact us](mailto:gdpr@atomsupplies.com) to let us know. 

We use the **information we collect** to:

  * administer our site and improve your browsing experience, including tailoring content offered to you; 
  * defend our rights or property and to protect the rights and interests of our consumers and users; and
  * as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure.

We use the **information we receive from other sources** to:

  * combine it with information you give to us and information we collect about you for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive). These are companies approved by you, such as social media sites.

In accordance with the law, we will only retain your personal information for the period necessary to accomplish the purpose for which it was provided. We keep this data under periodic review to ensure it is still necessary for us to retain it. If reasonably necessary or required to meet legal or regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce our terms and conditions, we may also keep hold of some of your information as required, even after you have closed your account or it is no longer needed to provide the services to you. We suspect that it won’t come as a galloping shock to you to learn that we record our incoming and outgoing telephone conversations with our customers and other third parties. We do so for the purposes of crime prevention, and in a way which is consistent with guidance issued by the Information Commissioner’s Office. All telephone records will be deleted from our records 6 months after the date of the relevant conversation. We reserve the right to share telephone records with law enforcement agencies, and we may also use those records for training purposes, but will otherwise keep them strictly confidential.  

### HOW DO WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION?

We may share your personal information with our affiliated companies and with trusted, strategic partners that help us run our business and improve our services and your customer experience, including matters such as warehousing and delivery, credit card and data processing, marketing and advertising, IT hosting and market research, and any trends, patterns or behaviours which might be useful to us in improving our website, content and advertising.   In order to ensure the security of your transactions and prevent or detect fraudulent transactions, we may also share your information with our fraud screening partners. We won’t otherwise share your personal data unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so.  **Be aware that our site includes social network plugins and links to third party content (including videos hosted by other sites), so certain data (your current IP address, e-mail address, pages or sites you visit after you leave our site and the date and time) is forwarded to these social media services and third party sites even if you are not registered with them. If you are already logged into the social media service when you click on the social media button, the social media service may also use this data to identify your user name and possibly even your real name. Unfortunately, we have no control over the extent, nature and purpose of such data processing or their privacy practices – we suggest you review their privacy statements to make sure your are comfortable with the way they use your information as well.** You can rest assured that we’ll only disclose your information for the specific purposes mentioned above and that your data security is being taken care of. These third parties are bound to process your personal data only on our strict instructions and, even then, only when they can offer adequate technical and organizational measures to protect it.  We may also disclose your personal information as necessary to protect the security and integrity of our site according with the law; in the event that we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets to a third party; or as required or authorised by law. As part of our participation in Google’s Certified Shops Programme, certain information relating to transactions undertaken on our website will be collected and processed by Google. We provide transaction information to Google to demonstrate that we deliver orders on time, have low occurrence of customer issues, and resolve customer issues quickly. As part of our participation in Trustpilot’s consumer review service, certain personal data of our customers is processed by Trustpilot for the purposes of obtaining and making available feedback regarding the quality of our customer service. Trustpilot is under a contractual obligation to implement the necessary security measures to ensure that our customers’ personal data is not lost, altered or damaged, accessed by unauthorised persons, misused or otherwise treated in violation of data protection law.

### SHARING INFORMATION OVERSEAS

We may transfer your personal information to service providers an strategic partners located in countries other than the one in which you live ( only to the extent that it is necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined above). But, worry not, we will take appropriate steps to provide an adequate level of protection using the standards set within the EEA as minimum. No matter where you reside, your data will be processed in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy and as required by the law.

### SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We adopt technical and organisational measures to protect your data as comprehensively as possible. In addition to the commitment of our employees to secrecy and a careful selection and monitoring of our service providers, who are bound to comply with high security standards for the protection of your personal data, we also secure our operating environment adequately.  To protect your data against unwanted access, we use data encryption. Data collected from this site will be passed between your computer and our server and vice versa via the internet using SHA256withRSA 2048 bit TLS (Transport Layer Security) encryption. In order to secure the transmission of sensitive bank and credit card details and to protect data from abusive use we utilize in transit encryption (SSL, Secure Socket Layer). Credit card data is stored in our database is also encrypted using RSA 2048 bit encryption.

### YOUR RIGHTS (AND HOW TO EXERCISE THEM!)

If you wish to exercise any of your statutory rights relating to data we hold about you, please get in touch by filling out [this form](https://app-de.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/4f3d67be-5b94-4fc8-bcf7-7ab1f0cd8ff5). We use the OneTrust portal to help us deal with all data-related requests so that we can deal with your query as thoroughly and promptly as possible. The form includes all of the information we require in order to deal with your request and includes a section where you can also insert any other details or questions you may have for us. Once we receive the form, you will receive an automated response from OneTrust. Thereafter, rest assured that we will be handling your request personally and we will let you know when we have completed the request. If you have any questions about filling out the form or encounter problems submitting it, please contact us at [gdpr@atomsupplies.com](mailto:gdpr@atomsupplies.com) and we will be happy to help. If you would like to exercise any of your statutory rights relating to data we hold about you, please fill out this form [here](https://app-de.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/4f3d67be-5b94-4fc8-bcf7-7ab1f0cd8ff5) to let us know.  Once we get all of the information we need to process your request, your request will be investigated by our Data Protection Officer.  A response will then be provided in writing within a reasonable period (we will always try to ensure this is no longer than within one month, but we may inform you should we need more time to process your request in certain circumstances). We promise that we will follow procedures so that we can deal fairly and promptly with your request. However, if you remain dissatisfied after we have processed your request, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/concerns/).  

### CONTACT US

Just so you know, our legal name is Atom Supplies Limited. We are registered in England and Wales with registration number 03193057 and VAT number GB 662241553. You can contact our Data Protection Officer [here](mailto:terri@atomsupplies.com).  If you no longer want to receive marketing information from us, simply follow the ‘unsubscribe instantly’ link in any e-mail we send to you or just [send us a quick email](mailto:gdpr@atomsupplies.com) with your request. Please bear in mind that even if you opt out, we may still continue to send you information that relates to any account or business relationship you may still have with us (for example, a request you have made about one of our lip-smacking whiskies). If you are seeking to exercise any of your statutory rights or if you have any comments, queries, or complaints about our collection or use of your personal information, please get in touch by filling out [this form](https://app-de.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/4f3d67be-5b94-4fc8-bcf7-7ab1f0cd8ff5). We use the OneTrust portal to help us deal with all data-related requests so that we can deal with your query as thoroughly and promptly as possible. The form includes all of the information we require in order to deal with your request and includes a section where you are welcome to insert any other details or questions you may have for us. Once we receive the form, you will receive an automated response from OneTrust. Thereafter, rest assured that we will be handling your request personally and we will let you know when we have completed the request. If you have any questions about filling out the form or encounter problems submitting it, please contact us at [gdpr@atomsupplies.com](mailto:gdpr@atomsupplies.com) and we will be happy to help.

**Please be aware that the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Any transmission of your data to our website is at your own risk.**

### CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

We keep our Privacy Policy under regular review. Any changes we may make to this Privacy Policy in the future will be posted here (you can access previous versions [here](https://www.masterofmalt.com/c/previous-privacy-policy/)). This Privacy Policy was last updated on 26 November 2018 and it’s version number 4.  Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to the privacy policy.

* * *

We use cookies and similar technologies to personalise and improve your experience when you use our website, including:

  * keeping track of your shopping basket;
  * allowing you to login to your account;
  * remembering your preferences; 
  * customising the website to be more relevant to you (like displaying prices in your country’s currency); and
  * helping us make our website better by telling us what users like and don’t like.

This document explains what these technologies are, why we use them and your rights to control our use of them.  This Cookie Policy is incorporated into our Privacy Policy. If you continue to browse the site without changing your settings, we’ll assume that you are happy to receive all cookies. However, you can change your cookie settings at any time by clicking here.  

### 1\. What are cookies?

A “cookie” is a small text file that’s stored on your device when you visit a website.  All of your devices have different cookie settings. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your device. 

Some cookies are deleted when you close down your browser. Others remain on your device until they expire or you delete them from your cache. These enable us to remember things about you as a returning visitor.

For more information about cookies, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) Alternatively, you can search the internet for other independent information on cookies.

Cookies can be set by us (“ **first party cookies** ”) or by selected other companies who place cookies on our site to enable features or functionality to be provided on or through the website you are using, such as advertising, interactive content and analytics (“ **third party cookies** ”). The third parties that set these third party cookies can recognise your device both when it visits our website and also when it visits certain other websites or services. These service providers are subject to confidentiality provisions with us to restrict their use and collection of any personal data. However, please note that we do not control these third party cookies and we suggest you read the third parties’ privacy policies to make sure you are happy.

### 2\. Why do we use cookies and other tracking technologies?

We use cookies and third party cookies for several reasons. Some cookies are required for technical reasons in order for our website to operate, and we refer to these as “strictly necessary” cookies. Other cookies enable us and the third parties we work with to track and target the interests of visitors to our website, and we refer to these as “performance” and “functionality” cookies. For example, we use cookies to tailor content and information that we may send or display to you and otherwise personalize your experience while interacting with our website and to otherwise improve the functionality of our services. Finally, third parties serve cookies through our website for advertising, analytics, and other purposes. This is described in more detail below.

### 3\. What categories of cookies may be used?

The specific types of first and third party cookies served through our website and the purposes they perform are described in further detail below:

#### **Strictly necessary cookies**

We need to use these cookies to make the website work and allow you to use some of its features, such as tracking page navigation to assist with linking back to different sections, signing up to a newsletter and enhancing security on site when submitting forms.  

You can set your browser to block or alert you about these (or any other) cookies, but some or all of the site won’t work.

If you really hate cookies this much, it’s probably best you close the website and clear all your cookies.  In fact, the web probably isn’t for you… Physical shops still exist, and you can be confident of your privacy there.  Well, apart from people recognising you. And Security cameras. Lots of security cameras. But apart from that you’re all good.

For a list of the cookies used on our site which fall under this category, click  here.

#### **Performance cookies**

These cookies are all about tracking site performance – we use them to do stuff like count visits, provide debugging information and see where visitors are coming from.

Typically these cookies just contain a unique ID which allows us and 3rd party services to recognise you as you move about the site and interact with it.  We (and 3rd party services) record all those interactions and tie them together using the unique IDs in these cookies.

If you turn these cookies off it’ll hamper our efforts, but nothing critical to you using the site should break.

For a list of the cookies used on our site which fall under this category, click here.

#### **Functional cookies**

These cookies are used to deliver enhanced functionality and features which we think are jolly valuable, but aren’t absolutely critical to making the website work (as in, you should still be able to buy stuff with these turned off), and they’re set both by us and 3rd party service we use.

You can turn these off, but some things won’t work or won’t work as well.

For a list of the cookies used on our site which fall under this category, click here.

#### **Targeting cookies**

Ok, these are the “bad” cookies everyone’s talking about.  They’re set by us and our advertising partners to help deliver targeted ads.

They may be used by us and our partners to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant adverts on other sites.  They do not store directly personal information, but are based on uniquely identifying your browser and internet device. If you do not allow these cookies, you will experience less targeted advertising.

But, before you click “deactivate” faster than a bourbon lover hitting “add to basket” when we get more Buffalo Trace Antique Collection into stock, just think about it for a moment – you’re not going to get **less** advertising, it’s just going to be less **targeted** – for which read “less relevant” – for which read “less useful”.

No one really likes advertising, and while we’d all prefer less of it, it’s a tough sell to say that it would be better for it to be less **relevant**.

That’s our pitch, now feel free to turn them off 🙂

For a list of the cookies used on our site which fall under this category, click here.

#### **Social Media cookies**

These cookies are set by social media services which appear on the site to enable you to share our content with your friends and networks. They are capable of tracking your browser across other sites and building up a profile of your interests. This may impact the content and messages you see on other websites you visit.  

If you do not allow these cookies you may not be able to use or see these sharing tools.

For a list of the cookies used on our site which fall under this category, click here.

#### **Other tracking technologies**

We and our third party partners may use other, similar technologies from time to time like web beacons, pixels (or “clear gifs”) and other tracking technologies. These are tiny graphics files that contain a unique identifier that enable us to recognise when someone has visited our website or, in the case of web beacons, opened an e-mail that we have sent them. This allows us, for example, to monitor the traffic patterns of users within our website, to understand whether you have come to our website from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party website, to serve targeted advertisements to you and others like you, to improve site performance, and to measure the success of marketing campaigns. While you may not have the ability to specifically reject or disable these tracking technologies, in many instances these technologies are reliant on cookies to function properly; accordingly, in those instances, declining cookies will impair functioning of these technologies.

Finally, please note that third parties (including providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies. Google also places and reads cookies on the browsers of users of our website (and may also use web beacons and similar technologies) to collect information relevant to the Google Certified Shops Programme. We have no control over these third parties.

For a list of the cookies used on our site which fall under this category, click here.

### 4\. How can I control cookies?

You have the right to decide whether to accept or reject cookies.

**Website cookie preference tool:** You can exercise preferences about what cookies are served on our website by clicking here.

**Browser controls:** You can set or amend your web browser controls to accept or refuse cookies. If you choose to reject cookies, you may still use our website though your access to some functionality and areas of our website may be restricted. Please click below for detailed information on how to disable and delete cookies in some commonly used browsers:

**Disabling most Interest Based Advertising:** Most advertising networks offer you a way to opt out of Interest Based Advertising. If you would like to find out more information, please visit[ www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://youronlinechoices.eu/).  

**Mobile Advertising:** You can opt out of having your mobile advertising identifiers used for certain types of Interest Based Advertising, including those performed by us, by accessing the settings in your Apple or Android mobile device and following the most recent published instructions. If you opt out, we will remove all data about you and no further data collection or tracking will occur. The random ID we (or our third party partners) had previously assigned to you will also be removed. This means that if at a later stage, you decide to opt-in, we will not be able to continue and track you using the same ID as before, and you will for all practical purposes be a new user to our system

### 5\. Changes to our Cookie Policy

This Cookie Policy was last updated on 26 November 2018. We may update it from time to time in order to reflect changes to the cookies we use or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons. Please therefore re-visit this Cookie Policy regularly to stay informed about our use of cookies and related technologies.
